Victor Rodriguez

323-381-4466 | victor.manuel.rodriguez.cs@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/victor-rodriguez-vr | github.com/Sudo-Victor-Victory

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Dynamic and Energetic Software Engineer, with 2 years of experience in developing financial products to achieve optimal quality, safety, and profitability. Focused, analytical, & eager to solve complex problems.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python, C++, C#, Golang, HTML, Javascript, Coldfusion, Prolog, SQL, Kotlin Libraries / Frameworks: Unity Engine, Hashicorp Vault, Pytest, Pillow, NodeJs, Selenium, Django,

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Jenkins, Jira, VS Code, Linux, Terraform, Shell, Visual Studio, PyCharm, IntelliJ

Experience

Bloomberg July 2022 - February 2024

Software Engineer

New York, NY

- Utilized Golang and Hashicorp Vault to develop a high performance, highly reliable & scalable SAAS Platform through Microservices to safely create, store, & retrieve sensitive data for 30+ critical teams in the trading space.
- Created a REST API for internal clients, promoting seamless integration with the internal cloud network, increasing adoption rates by 60%.
- Implemented Docker for local development, streamlining deployments and ensuring higher code quality, automating the process and reducing deployment time by an average of 3 hours.
- Improved stability of code by using Test Driven Development, Unit Tests, Automated Tests, & Integration Tests with Python, Pytest, & followed CI/CD best practices to provide consistent delivery of stable & reliable software.
- Implemented robust telemetry features to gather and analyze files & logs to identify potential failures sources through the use of various troubleshooting tools such as Splunk & Grafana to ensure quality to clients
- Produced a web-based front-end website using React that allowed internal clients to manage their SAAS instances

BNY Mellon

June 2021 – August 2021 Remote

START Developer Intern- Full Stack

- Built & deployed a web application to help 5,000 Business Administrators manage & mitigate company risks.
- Collaborated with stakeholders, database administrators, to discuss faults in a SQL Risk Database- correctly assessing that a Risk database needed stronger access controls, backups, robust monitoring, & a recovery plan.
- Effectively and quickly learned the necessary HTML, CSS, SQL, and UX/UI skills to meet requirements & deadlines despite no prior web development exposure in a legacy code-filled environment with a global team.

College of Engineering

June 2020 - June 2021

COE EXCEL Peer Mentor

California State University Long Beach, CA

- Mentored a group of 5-9 freshmen students each semester for Academic Excellence and Successful Leadership.
- Lead weekly study sessions, check-ins, and workshops to provide insight on topics such as: class scheduling, time management, and study skills. In addition to being selected as head mentor I trained incoming mentors.
- Debugged & peer reviewed code from students visiting the College of Engineering's tutoring center, explained core CS topics like Algorithms, & developed student's understanding & problem solving skills with Bloom's Taxonomy.

Projects

Windows XP Pipe Screensaver Recreation | C#, Unity Engine, Git

- Developed a Unity simulation to recreate the classic Windows XP Pipe Screensaver.
- Implemented a variable object model system to use other Geometric models such as Cubes, Triangles, and more.
- Extensively utilized version control systems (GIT) to return to track changes, and have backups for recovery.

EDUCATION

California State University, Long Beach

Long Beach, CA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Overall GPA: 3.5

Aug 2018 - May 2022

Awards and Leadership

Academic Chair

Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers

California State University, Long Beach

August 2021- May 2022

Secretary

Association for Computing Machinery

California State University, Long Beach

June 2020 - June 2021